Finding Aid for Rebecca Shelley Papers 1890-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Periodicals
  - "Greenwood" (Battle Creek) (incomplete), 1975-1978 (Box 15)
  - "In Fact,", 1941-1943; 24 issues (Box 15)
  - "Information from the Peace Movement of the German Democratic Republic,", 1964-1978; 9 issues (Box 15)
  - "Information Bulletin of the Christian Peace Conference,", 1965-1968; 4 issues (Box 15)
  - "The Last Call,", 1953-1955; 14 issues (Box 15)
  - "The Last Call,", 1956; 5 issues (Box 15)
  - 'Memo" (WSP), 1965-1969; 6 issues (Box 15)
  - "No More Hiroshimas,", 1956-1959; 14 issues (Box 15)
  - "No More Hiroshimas,", 1960-1966; 15 issues (Box 15)
  - "Panchayat Aur Insan,", 1971-1975; 4 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace Action,", 1939-1940; 1950-1960; 38 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace Garden Progress Report,", 1959-1964; 5 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace News,", 1947; 1956-1958; 1965-1966; 12 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace Newsletter" (New Delhi), 1966-1967; 5 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace Pilgrim's Progress,", 1955-1960; 6 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peace Review,", 1954-1955; 9 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peacemaker,", 1955-1966; 1973; 24 issues (Box 15)
  - "Peoples' Voices" (Costa Rica), 1972-1973; 4 issues (Box 15)
  - "Plowshare Press,", 1976 (Box 15)
    (vol. 1 no. 1-vol. 1 no. 2)
  - "Prevent World War III,", 1950-1955; 4 issues (Box 15)
  - "Serving Mankind,", 1957-1958; 10 issues 1-10 (Box 15)
  - "SSRS Newsletter,", 1955-1960; 22 issues (Box 15)
  - "Today,", January 1951-January 1952; 1 volumes (Box 15)
  - "Today,", February 1952-January 1957; 24 issues (Box 15)
  - "Toward A World Disarmament,", 1956; 5 issues (Box 15)
  - "Toward Freedom,", 1953; 1965; 1972-1973; 9 issues (Box 15)
  - "The Trumpet,", 1955 (Box 15)
  - "Unitarian-Universalist Fellowship of Battle Creek News," (incomplete), 1961-1968 (Box 15)
  - U.S.C.A.M. Newsletters, 1951-1955; 21 issues (Box 15)
  - "Veterans Stars and Stripes for Peace,", 1968-1970; 3 issues (Box 15)
  - "Vet's Voice for Peace,", 1955-1956; 5 issues (Box 15)
  - "Vietnam" (WIDF), 1965-1967; 10 issues (Box 15)
  - "Vietnam" (WIDF), 1968-1970; 10 issues (Box 15)
  - "Women of the Whole World,", 1965; 2 issues (Box 15)
  - "Women of Vietnam,", 1968; 1973; 2 issues (Box 15)
  - "Women's Peace Movement Bulletin,", March 1962-April 1963; 9 issues (Box 15)
  - "Women's Peace Movement Bulletin,", May 1963-May 1964; 11 volumes (Box 15)
  - "World Federation,", 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - "World Federation-Now,", 1939-1950; 11 issues (Box 15)
  - "WRL News,", 1955-1958; 1969; 13 issues (Box 15)
- Diaries and Notebooks
  The Diaries And Notebooks series includes eighteen diary volumes, a scrapbook of clippings and congratulatory letters presented to Shelley upon her 87th birthday, a student notebook from 1943, and several miscellaneous notebooks. Most of the diaries contain only brief and scattered entries. The earliest volume, covering 1936-1939, is a notable exception. This volume contains longer entries which discuss her marital difficulties and separation, her problems in writing novels and poems, and her citizenship case.
  - Diaries
    - 1936-1961, 9 volumes (Box 16)
    - 1962-1976, 9 volumes (Box 16)
  - Birthday Scrapbook, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Student Notebook, 1943-1944 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Notebooks (Box 16)
- Photographs
  Photographs are plentiful and span from approximately 1890 to 1980. There are photographs of Shelley at all stages of life, the Shelly family of various individuals, groups and events. Postcards are also located in this series.
  - Rebecca Shelley (Box 17)
    - circa 1897-1930 (Box 17)
    - 1931-1955 (Box 17)
    - 1956-1967 (Box 17)
    - 1968-1984 (Box 17)
  - Shelly Family
    - circa 1890-1929 (Box 17)
    - 1930-1980 (Box 17)
  - Persons Identified
    - A-G (includes Jane Addams and Emily Balch) (Box 17)
    - H-W (includes Alice Herz, J.H. Kellogg, Emil Mazey, Angela Morgan, Rosika Schwimmer, Lella Secor, and Eleanor Roosevelt) (Box 17)
    - Felix Rathmer (Box 17)
    - Franz Willman (Box 17)
  - Persons Unidentified
    - General (Box 17)
    - American Women (Box 17)
  - Groups (Box 17)
  - Rebecca Shelley with Friends, 1907-1914 (Box 17)
  - International Congress of Women, 1915 (Box 17)
    (includes Jane Addams)
  - Honeymoon at Yellowstone, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Camping, 1920s (Box 17)
  - Electric Works, 1920s (Box 17)
  - Milan Free Fair Peace Exhibit, circa 1954 (Box 17)
  - Peace Protests, circa 1957; circa 1965; circa 1979 (Box 17)
  - Peaceways, mostly dedication ceremony, 1959 (Box 17)
  - South Asian Expedition, 1971-1973
    - Meeting officials (Box 17)
    - Peaceway International agricultural program (Box 17)
    - Picketing (Box 17)
    - Vigils and wreath laying (Box 17)
    - With Indian people (Box 17)
  - Michigan International Citizen Award, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Postcards (Box 17)
- Writings
  Writings is a large series, measuring four-and-a-half linear feet. However, all but the first five inches is made up of unsorted manuscripts of novels and poems written by Shelley. The five inches which are sorted begin with Shelley's four books: A Widows Mite, 1961, Je m'accuse, 1968, In Mourning, 1971, and I Confess, undated. There are two folders containing autobiographical sketches, drafts, and research notes from an autobiography that was never completed. There are also two folders of statements, open letters, and appeals, mostly from the 1960s and 1970s. Much of Shelley's poetry has been arranged alphabetically and is located in four folders in this series.
  - Books: A Widow's Mite,; Je m'accuse,; In Mourning,; I Confess, 1961; 1968; 1971; undated (Box 17)
  - Autobiographical Sketches and Drafts, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Statements, Open Letters, and Appeals, 1960s; 1970s; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Poetry, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Manuscripts of novels and poems by Rebecca Shelley (unsorted) (Box 18)
  - Manuscripts of novels and poems by Rebecca Shelley (unsorted) (Box 19)
    (continued)
  - Manuscripts of novels and poems by Rebecca Shelley (unsorted) (Box 20)
  - Manuscripts of novels and poems by Rebecca Shelley (unsorted) (Box 21)
Partial Index to Correspondence, 1984 accession
Arnori, M.S. (Minority of One)
February 21, 1966, February 23, 1966, February 28, 1966
Balch, Emily Greene, 1867-1961.
June 15, 1933, January 24, 1937, January 27, 1937, March 29, 1937, April 11, 1937, April 28, 1937, May 30, 1937, June 18, 1937, July 5, 1937, July 18, 1937, July 20, 1937, December 20, 1937, December 30, 1937, May 1939, January 15, 1942, September 11, 1950, April 23, 1951
Bentley, Alvin Morell, 1918-1969.
October 10, 1962
Brown, Garry Eldridge, 1923-
August 11, 1970, August 13, 1971, December 22, 1971, January 18, 1972
Circle Pines Center.
August 5, 1963
Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-
December 17, 1954, April 27, 1959, April 18, 1961, September 18, 1961, November 17, 1961, 1962 (7), 1963 (5), April 4, 1964, May 19, 1964, April 9, 1965, May 20, 1965, March 2, 1967
Dende, Leopold
August 28, 1963, September 11, 1963, September 21, 1963, 1965 (17), September 11, 1966, June 4, 1967
Dougherty, Peter
April 14, 1979, undated 1970s (2)
Dubina, Nestor
1965 (5)1966 (6)
Eddy, Robert M.
May 1964 (4), September 1964 (2), May 2, 1965
Eldred, Mary
May 21, 1962, September 23, 1962, December 23, 1963, July 10, 1967, undated 1970s, September 6, 1972, September 7, 1972, January 4, 1973, January 1, 1974, June 1, 1978, January 17, 1981, 1983 (8)
Florence, Barbara Moench
September 26, 1976, September 21, 1976, June 9, 1977, October 15, 1976, February 3, 1980, February 28, 1980, November 24, 1980
Florence, Philip
July 25, 1966, July 18, 1966
Gage-Colby, Ruth
undated 1960's, June 22, 1962, July 4, 1962, July 8, 1962, July 27, 1962, June 2, 1963, 1964 (6), January 15, 1965, April 14, 1965, June 21, 1965, November 1, 1965, October 13, 1966
Hamilton, Alice, 1869-1970.
October 13, 1966
Harrington, Donald Szantho, 1914-
May 25, 1957, May 30, 1957, June 6, 1957, 1958 (9), May 15, 1959, September 9, 1959, undated 1960s, November 16, 1960, 1962 (8)
Harrison, Alice
undated 1960s, July 2, 1958, October 22, 1958, 1959 (6), February 3, 1960, February 5, 1960, June 29, 1960, August 3, 1960, 1962 (5), 1963 (7), 1964 (10), 1965 (5), June 10, 1966, December 2, 1966, May 7, 1967, June 15, 1967, November 29, 1968, January 18, 1969, January 29, 1970, November 6, 1980
Hassler, Alfred
May 11, 1962, April 30, 1962, July 7, 1962, February 10, 1964, February 26, 1964, March 25, 1964, March 30, 1964, April 14, 1964, April 2, 1965, undated 1960s
Herz, Alice
August 6, 1956, September 13, 1958, January 22, 1959, March 7, 1961, August 13, 1961, 1962 (8), 1963 (5), 1964 (extensive), 1965
Herz, Helga
July 2, 1967
Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964.
May 13, 1957, May 15, 1957, May 20, 1957, may 23, 1957, June 1, 1959, June 11, 1959, May 2, 1963, May 21, 1963, May 23, 1963, June 4, 1963
Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, 1911-1978.
October 21, 1968
Hutchinson, Paul, 1890-1956.
November 16, 1936, November 10, 1936, October 14, 1936, May 1, 1939
Kamarck, Frank and Esther
1957-1960, May 20, 1962, June 28, 1962, undated 1970s, undated 1950s
Kennedy, Robert Francis, 1925-1968.
March 12, 1968, March 19, 1968
Labadie, Charles Joseph Antoine dit, 1850-
February 2, 1928, February 24, 1928, February 26, 1928
Laubach, Frank Charles, 1884-1970.
undated 1960s, September 21, 1960, February 15, 1961, March 17, 1962, March 22, 1962, April 17, 1962, August 10, 1962, August 20, 1963, March 24, 1964, April 4, 1964, May 19, 1964, March 16, 1965, March 25, 1965
Lehman, Barbara
January 1964 (6), February 25, 1964
Lindsey, Fanny Cole
July 3, 1945, 1946, 1947
Lloyd, William B (Jr.)
March 29, 1929, January 29, 1968, May 26, 1968, December 11, 1968, November 19, 1968, November 29, 1968, April 19, 1971
Lochner, Louis Paul, 1887-
May 3, 1943
Mazey, Emil, 1913-
May 19, 1962, April 27, 1962
Milliken, William Grawn, 1922-
December 18, 1970
Minkoff, Lynn
June-August 1963, April 14, 1964, June 11, 1964, July 6, 1964, September 5, 1964, 1965 (5), August 10, 1966, September 21, 1966
Morgan, Angela, 1874-1957.
undated 1950s, December 1954-January 1957
Mygatt, Tracy, 1885-1973.
undated 1960s, March 31, 1962
Nielson, Axel
April 20, 1958, May 11, 1958, September 18, 1958, December 24, 1958, January 3, 1959, January 4, 1959, January 3, 1962, February 1, 1962, August 20, 1963, March 25, 1968, June 30, 1968, April 29, 1969
O'Brien, Patrick Henry, 1868-1959.
February 17, 1936, July 20, 1944
O'Connor, Jessie Lloyd
March 24, 1965, September 7, 1965, September 19, 1968
Olmstead, Mildred Scott
September 11, 1950, October 5, 1965, November 6, 1956
Pauling, Linus, 1901-
April 2, 1964
Puri, J.N.
January 14, 1971, 1974, 1975, November 10, 1977, December 20, 1978, 1979, January 25, 1980, December 25, 1981
Randall, Mercedes
January 19, 1974, April 16, 1974, May 16, 1960, July 8, 1963, September 23, 1963, February 27, 1965
Rathmer, Felix Martin, -1959.
1922-1924, 1938-1939, undated, 1911-1949
Reynolds, Barbara
June 1963-1965, January 27, 1966, February 2, 1968, April 11, 1968, January 10, 1978
Romney, George Wilcken, 1907-
June 20, 1967, September 14, 1967
Secor, Lella Faye, d.1966.
January 15, 1960, January 13, 1961, January 13, 1941, January 15, 1941
Selskosojus, Inc.
May 15, 1926, July 1, 1926
Sexton, Kripp
March 30, 1965, undated 1970s
Shafer, Paul Werntz, 1893-1954.
March 14, 1948, March 20, 1948
Shapiro, Samuel
November 26, 1962, December 2, 1962, August 28, 1963
Shelly, Edna
April 18, 1950, January 4, 1939, January 10, 1939, April 21, 1963, July 15, 1964
Shelly, Florence
undated, 1911-1949, May 24, 1939, August 7, 1942, July 1943, September 1943, 1944, 1945, April 26, 1965, June 27, 1966, November 29, 1968
Shelly, Paul
August 2, 1961, February 24, 1973, undated 1970s, February 25, 1973, March 1, 1973, 1974, May 11, 1975, August 9, 1975, December 10, 1975, July 25, 1978, July 30, 1978, December 5, 1978, August 25, 1979, November 4, 1979, February 4, 1980, January 5, 1981, February 9, 1981, August 16, 1981, 1983 (5), February 19, 1984
Shelly, Will
August 8, 1918, March 4, 1939, undated 1970s, February 3, 1975, November 1979
Shibata, Shingo
July 22, 1966, January 16, 1978
Staebler, Neil, 1905-
October 15, 1962
Steinson, Barbara
August 20, 1974, November 3, 1974
Todd, Paul Harold, 1921-
April 4, 1966, August 29, 1966
Turn Toward Peace.
December 4, 1962, August 2, 1962, May 23, 1962, December 26, 1962
September 18, 1963, October 18, 1963, December 5, 1963
U.S. Farmers Association.
October 17, 1964, November 18, 1964, December 5, 1964, December 14, 1964, January 7, 1965
Van Koevering, Adrian, 1874-1961.
1921-1927
War Resisters League.
January 7, 1933, January 26, 1933
Weinberger, Harry, 1886
February 8, 1939, February 14, 1939, February 17, 1939
Wilson, Charles Carroll
1964-1966
Witherspoon, Frances M, 1886-1973.
March 6, 1961, March 13, 1963, September 21, 1966
Women Strike for Peace.
July 27, 1963, October 29, 1964, September 8, 1965
Woodruff, Alice
October 24, 1962, January 5, 1963, December 19, 1970, September 20, 1973, January 27, 1977, January 28, 1977, February 23, 1978
Wynner, Edith
March 1965-August 1965, March-September 1966, August 16, 1979, January 20, 1964